demosphere.com 2018-03-05

# Privacy Policy | Demosphere

The below Privacy Policy is Demosphere’s standard Privacy Policy which describes information collected through Demosphere’s system by Demosphere Clients.

### General

Demosphere International, Inc. (“Demosphere”, collectively, “we,” “us,” and “our”) are sensitive to the private nature of information you provide to us over the Internet. This Privacy Policy governs the websites operated by us and explains how we treat personal information we collect about you and your family (collectively, “you” or “your”) when you visit this website. Please read our Privacy Policy carefully. Except as otherwise indicated in this policy, we will not sell, share, license, trade or rent your personal information to others. BY USING THIS WEBSITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OF THE PROCESSING OF YOUR AND YOUR FAMILY’S PERSONAL DATA IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THIS WEBSITE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THIS WEBSITE FOLLOWING THE POSTING OF CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY WILL MEAN THAT YOU ALSO ACCEPT THOSE CHANGES.

### Information We Collect

**General.**  When you register your child on this website , we will be collecting personal information from you about your family and your child. The personal information we collect may include your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and credit card number, as well as personal information about your child, such as his or her name, address, school, grade level, birth date, gender, and any known allergies.

We only request information that is required to ensure that you or your child can effectively and safely join and participate in a sport or other activity, and do not condition your child’s participation on the disclosure of more information than is reasonably necessary.

**Children.**  We appreciate the need to further privacy protections with respect to personal information we collect regarding your children on our sites and applications. While no information should be submitted over this website by visitors under 18 without the consent of their parent or legal guardian, and while we do not knowingly collect personal information from children, we nonetheless undertake additional steps to protect children’s privacy including, but not limited to, notifying parents regarding our information practices (i.e., types of information collected and how we utilize that information), obtaining parental consent as described below, and limiting the collection of personal information relating to your child to no more than is reasonably necessary to participate in the designated activity. We encourage young people to check with their parents before entering information on any website, including ours.  
**  
Website Usage Information.**  Our web servers automatically collect website usage information from you when you visit our website. Website usage information informs us about how our visitors and subscribers use and navigate our websites, including the number and frequency of visitors and subscribers to each web page, and the length of their stays.  
_  
Tracking Tools._  We use certain internet technologies such as “cookies,” “action keys” and “web bugs,” among others (collectively, “Tracking Tools”) to assist our individual users in their use of our sites. Tracking Tools are files or tools that are placed on your computer in order to identify your Web browser and the activities of your computer on our Websites, and as a method to safeguard the authenticity of your secure session while logged in as a user. By visiting our Websites, you agree that we can place these types of cookies and other Tracking Tools on your device. The information obtained from use of these technologies is not sold or otherwise provided to any third parties.

### How We Use Information Collected

Demosphere may use and disclose the personal information you provide about your family and your child to enable us to process, validate and verify your request to register you or your child in a sport or other activity. Demosphere may disclose the personal information collected to the applicable state and/or national sport associations or other third parties for insurance and other purposes necessary to successfully operate the organization for which you are registering. With regard to Demosphere, any such use of the personal information you provide will be made only at the direction of the organization for which you are registering.

We may also share such information (a) to the extent necessary to comply with any legal or regulatory requirements; (b) at the request of any governmental authority investigating a crime; or (c) otherwise with your express permission. Please note that we may transfer this information (a) among any companies or organizations affiliated with us, but only to the extent necessary to complete your or your child’s registration in other leagues or teams; (b) to successors or potential successors in interest; and (c) to any independent contractors we engage to assist with or perform any of the foregoing activities or any activities related to compliance with and enforcement of this policy. We reserve the right to contact you regarding on-line registration related problems or questions as well as to provide you with information regarding changes to our terms and conditions, to our Privacy Policy, or to other policies that affect you and your use of the website.

### Your Ability to Choose

**A Parent’s right to choose.**  Parents and guardians have the right to consent to the collection and use of their child’s personal information without consenting to the disclosure of that information to third parties other than as described in this Privacy Policy. In recognition of this right, please understand that we will verify the authority to receive information from you by requiring a signed consent form which should be returned to us at the address provided herein below. We may also contact you by phone for an additional oral verification.

### Security

**  
General.**  The personal information we collect regarding you and your family is stored in limited access servers. We maintain safeguards to ensure the security, integrity, and privacy of these servers and of the personal information we collect. Each page on our website containing personal information is encrypted in transmission using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, and we maintain a thawte Secure Server ID. From time to time, we review our security protocols to consider implementing new technologies and methods to safeguard your personal information. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect the personal information collected, we cannot ensure or warrant the confidentiality or security of any information transmitted to us, and you provide any such information to us at your own risk.

**Links to affiliated or third party websites.**  We may make content from affiliated websites or other third party websites available to you from links located on our websites. These third party websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy and are neither owned nor controlled by us. We do not endorse these sites, are not responsible for the privacy policies of other sites that may collect your personal information, and strongly recommend that you review the privacy policy at each such website to determine how that website protects your and your family’s privacy.

### Review and Correction

You may review, alter or update the personal information about your family that you provide to us at any time by contacting the organization for which you are registering. If you desire that we no longer use such personal information, please contact us at optout@demosphere.com, and we will make all reasonable efforts to purge or suppress such personal information from our databases.

### Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the future in any material respect, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy without your prior consent.

### Dispute Resolution and Choice of Law

You agree that any controversy or claim arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy shall be governed and construed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Virginia, without regard to its choice of law rules. You further consent to the jurisdiction and venue of the Eastern District of Virginia in connection with any and all actions arising out of this Privacy Policy. Lastly, you agree that you may not bring a claim nor assert a cause of action against Demosphere, in any forum or manner, more than one (1) year after the cause of action accrued, except where you could not have reasonably discovered the wrong giving rise to the claim within one year.

### Limitation of Liability

BY USING OUR WEBSITES, YOU AGREE THAT IN NO EVENT SHALL DEMOSPHERE BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES WHETHER BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT, OR OTHER LEGAL THEORY, IN CONNECTION WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE WEBSITES. EXCEPT FOR GROSS NEGLIGENCE OR WILLFUL MISCONDUCT ON THE PART OF DEMOSPHERE, IN NO EVENT SHALL DEMOSPHERE BE LIABILE TO YOU IN CONNECTION WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE WEBSITES FOR ANY AMOUNT.

### Comments and Questions

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at:

Demosphere International, Inc.  
306 N Washington St.  
Falls Church, VA 22046  
(703) 536-1600  
info@demosphere.com

If you are not over eighteen (18) years of age, you must have a parent or legal guardian contact us on your behalf.

This policy was last updated on November 1, 2013.
